hello everybody and welcome to another
week of Holo talk Our Guest this week is
a Mr X who wants to remain anonymous and
uh Mr X is a collector of holography
that's quite a impressive collection of
holograms and he's to talk to us a
little bit about getting started
collecting and a few of the display
techniques he has including some of the
actual pieces that he has in his
collection so that's Mr X this week
coming up moment
our next guest is going to be Dr jiong
from Lake Forest College and this will
be the week of March 29th so you'll want
to tune in for that special show as well
so like I promised in our other shows
we're not going to take up a lot of Chit
Chat when we get started so we're going
to go right to the interview just just
set up we had a hard time hearing one
another and it was strange because he
had a hard time hearing me I had a hard
time hearing him and the thing is the
way that it turns out on the tables I'm
talking into a microphone so when it's
recorded
hear me very well
and Mr X on the other hand because he
was also coming through the console and
his voice didn't come through as loud as
I would have hoped it would but I took
it into the sound editing program and
tried to give him a little bit of a
boost so hopefully it's not that hard to
hear what it is that we're talking about
so uh
I'm just going to let the interview play
I'm not going to come back on after it's
over I just want to thank you for tuning
in once again to another week of whole
talk and here is the interview with Mr X
today you know wow
so we're on the line with Mr X
you want to remain anonymous I can
understand that I imagine you have some
very valuable pieces and
in case you want to go broadcast and who
you are or where your thumbs on the net
so I can understand that and I'll
respect that but I know who you are
thank you I Know Who You Are
why don't you tell us a little bit about
how you got started collecting Holograms
because I imagine there's going to be a
lot of people that's going to log on
that are collectors they may collect
watches they may collect paper like
magazines and postcards
and they're going to be interested in
hearing what this is all about is this a
new area of collecting obviously not for
us yeah but how did you get started
collecting three-dimensional Holograms
well actually I think it started when I
was um at a mall and they at one
particular store I think it was called
World Bazaar something like that or one
of those Science High School and stores
they had Holograms there
always just you know immediately
attracted to them it just really seemed
interesting was this a couple years ago
well this is like 11 years ago so okay
yeah
and uh following that
somehow I got a hold of a catalog scores
where I ordered some via the mail
and uh I think it was
let's see what was the name of the place
something like 3D light Gallery okay
and I ordered from that way and
then I started getting interested in
um
pursuing it further and I found uh I
located a few places like um
Museum of holography in Chicago
and they have
periodic changes of the you know the
exhibitions there they have some really
nice
so you you also not just commercial
pieces that someone would find maybe
over in one of the malls but you also
have some of the art pieces yeah I do
yeah I like I've got pieces like by
Larry Lieberman mm-hmm
I like I've got like primary woman and a
number of others by him
uh I've got
Crystal dreams I think it's called
it's really a nice little head that has
like a couple of pod years with their
you know it's a type of a sponsor like
related to the chamber Nautilus oh I see
and I collect uh fossils so I was really
excited about that one now are they
mostly reflection Holograms
now I've got one uh transmission
hologram
Dr John Perry Oh yeah holographics North
I think is it one of his large format
holder games yeah I think it's pretty
big 26 by 26 or something like that it's
uh it's called the painter and it's uh
like a full color hologram and it's
animated where the guy
and about two feet out of the picture in
the air with a paintbrush oh my goodness
that's a really nice one uh John Perry
is going to be a guest on the show in
the upcoming week wow yeah so we'll have
to talk about some of his large format
work where would you display these
Holograms in your home yeah I have them
all in one room uh on three walls and in
the middle of the room I've got my
computer desk everything so it's kind of
neat let's see yeah uh I really have a
lot of the Holograms right next to each
other because I have so many and you
know with kind of limited based on what
I kind of divide
developed recently is I hang these
strips from the ceiling
uh in between the halogen light bulb
that it helps to block some of the
lights okay and it doesn't you know uh
so you don't get any crosstalk yeah you
know with the way the you know how you
have to have a single beam what size are
the panels so I used black cardboard
panels you know just like from Walmart
and they're like oh about like seven or
eight inches wide and they hang down
about like a foot and a half and this
allows you to pack your Holograms
closely together you know you don't have
that interference between you know with
the different light and occurring with
each other especially the image plain
Holograms the ones that stick out you
know they really don't tolerate that
well at all and you don't want to get
multiple images with those so let me
explain to the listeners that when you
illuminate a hologram you have to have a
single light source
and it should be fairly good distance
away so that when the Hologram looks at
the light it sees a pin source of light
emanating from the fixture and what
happens in a lot of settings is that
when you get your Holograms too close
bread of that light actually begins to
touch the Holograms that are located on
the left hand side and the right hand
side of the one that's being illuminated
and each one of those lights creates its
own image
and it's not a very nice effect to view
yeah but you seem to have gotten around
that quite a bit yeah it worked really
well because you're going to have some
you know that pictures that are actually
touching each other except for the Mad
in between
even though you know it divides it
really well that way it's amazing how
well that works now you're so pleased
with that because before it was so
frustrating you know you get double
images and it just didn't work well I
think a lot of stores should try that
too because I've noticed even you know
with certain doors and things and you
know I've seen that it doesn't have the
same problem I think it's some of those
places use that it would help
uh yeah I've got some other Holograms
that are multi-colored like from uh Hans
to delgagen yep from Lake forth college
and those are really nice
I really like those because they seem
like it looks like the real thing is
right there it almost seems like there's
a hole in the wall and you're looking
also you know there's
it's just a really nice hologram so
there's hardly any grainy appearance
like you might get in certain holograms
for really clean and well done
you have a full color Holograms are
absolutely incredible yeah
you just think that whatever it is that
you're looking at is right in front of
you yeah it seems like it what type of
Lights do you use are they special
fixtures or just the type that like I I
have a lot of different track fixtures
yeah I use the tracks also and uh for
some of I use the halves and Bulbs
usually like 75 Watts 50 Watts I think
they're like mr16s or something right am
I 16 and for some of those it depends
there's certain Holograms that don't
even work well with those because they
they're hazy regardless even if you use
those why what I do is I put
um small aluminum like just out of
aluminum foil uh pieces right on the
lens part in the front part of the bulb
and then I put a little lit in those
with scissors you know
and that seems to work but you got to
really watch with that because you can
overheat a halogen boom so you can you
only have to you have to fix it on there
fixate it just with you know the
slightest amount of aluminum foil
because if you put too much it just
overheats
I've had mine well they started to you
know give off the smell from smoke or
something because they have to watch
with that I know you follow a lot of
different things with holography
including some of the theories of Dr
David bone and some of the other people
that uh
yeah
well when he was alive he was a
professor of theoretical physics and he
had some really
unique ideas about you know the
relationship between Holograms and the
universe and how possibly the cosmos
this holographic in nature and uh that
was really interesting talking to him
and discussing philosophy with him
there's a really good book if people
would be interested that deals with uh
some of his ideas and with Holograms and
that kind of a thing and it's fairly
simple you know in terms of reading it's
all Looking Glass Universe okay and uh f
David T and uh John Briggs are the
author okay
there's a Looking Glass Universe Looking
Glass universe and a couple other titles
they may want to look into is a
wholeness in the implicate order yeah
that's fine I think I think he did that
maybe in conjunction with the
krishnamurti right yeah krishnamurti is
a philosopher he passed away also but
some of his uh ideas are really
appreciative of too because he deals a
lot with holistic aspects of things and
how The Observers he observed
you know that's one of the principles
that he talks about which is really
interesting he talks about how people
can have superficial minds and it's
interesting when you think about the
fact that people a lot of people are
just happy with
two-dimensional pictures and you know
they don't have Minds with much depth
but it seems like uh hologram offer more
you know
people just need to look more deeply
what if for our listeners that are on
here maybe for the first time
um what tips would you give to someone
that with buying home with with getting
started because it can be expensive for
some of the better pieces yeah well
there's a really when I first started I
mostly did get just a smaller films and
there are some really good film
Holograms that are just outstanding and
they're you know relatively inexpensive
you can really get super holograms for a
decent price
some of them are really you know
philosophically oriented I think like
there's a lot of film Holograms
that are inexpensive that deal a lot of
with uh like empty ushers work oh yeah
yeah this stuff is just unbelievable in
terms of relating you know philosophy
and that kind of a thing so
um
Third Dimension limited made a lot of
the one by him that I have and you can
get those
you know from various sources uh you
know on your
in your whole Museum website there's
some places that you can link on to that
have so
mm-hmm you know they're really nice yeah
they're easy to order now on the net you
know it's very convenient because there
aren't a lot of holography shops yeah
it's not like every neighborhood has one
yeah it's an art form or whatever you'd
want to call it that's not appreciated
Enough by people it's just a shame in a
way because it really is so beautiful
and
you know there's a lot of implications
with it philosophically and all
I don't know it's just people don't seem
to appreciate it as much as it should be
but maybe someday that'll change
hopefully I think so
we are in the age that people will look
back on and we'll probably consider
ourselves very lucky that we had the
opportunity to live during the time that
we live you have a lot of memories
well I want to thank you for being a
guest Mr X yeah thank you and uh you get
a lot of people to come on and hear what
it is that you have to say about
collecting Holograms and maybe perhaps
you've inspired a few people out there
to get started on their own
there were more information about
collecting there's a lot of information
on collecting other things yeah you know
you can buy books to find out what year
something was made and what serial
numbers with it and you know how many
were made
and hopefully someday maybe we'll see
something like that with a lot of yeah
that would be great well what I'm going
to do is I'm going to say good night to
the listeners and then I'm going to rip
these headphones off and grab a hold of
you before we hang up okay okay so hold
on okay thanks for tuning in folks